### Contact

8642802564 (Mobile) ewiegert99@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ethan-wiegert (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Open Al

Redux

Web Development

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

# **Ethan Wiegert**

Software Developer | JavaScript | C# | React | SQL

Atlanta, Georgia, United States

# Summary

As a Software Developer, I leverage my skills to build engaging and full-stack applications. I also have experience in integrating Open AI API to enhance the functionality and interactivity of my projects.

Before becoming a Software Developer, I completed a software engineering bootcamp at Thinkful, where I learned industry best practices and standards, focusing on JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, algorithms, and data structures. I also hold a BS in Microbiology from Clemson University, which gives me an advantage in working in a fast-paced environment and delivering results with quality in mind.

# Experience

Lexicon Tech Solutions Software Developer April 2024 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Full-stack developer emphasizing in C#, Blazor, SQL, Javascript, HTML5, and CSS.

#### Freelance

Freelance Software Engineer
December 2023 - April 2024 (5 months)

Decide-My-Dinner Application | https://github.com/ethanwiegert/decide-my-dinner

- -Built a React Application to aid in selecting what restaurant to eat at.
- -Implemented conditionally rendering features.
- -Integrated Open Al API into "Find My Dinner" feature.
- -Integrated React Redux into application.
- -Technology: React, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Open Al API, Redux

### Thinkful

Software Engineering Student
June 2023 - December 2023 (7 months)

Page 1 of 3

Acquired comprehensive knowledge of industry best practices and software development standards, focusing on JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, algorithms, and data structures.

Recipe Tracker Application | https://github.com/ethanwiegert/project-recipe-tracking-app

- -Built a React application to allow saving recipe information.
- -Implemented the single responsibility principle with React components.
- -Technology: React, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap

Encryption/Decryption Application | https://github.com/ethanwiegert/decoderring

- -Built out an application that takes user inputs and encodes them into secret messages using several encoding algorithms
- -Implemented feature to decode encoded messages
- -Technology: Javascript ES6, HTML5, Node.js

Responsive AirBnB Frontend Application | https://github.com/ethanwiegert/frontend-foundations

- -Built a frontend lookalike of AirBnB static website with responsive views for mobile, tablets and desktop
- -Technology: HTML, CSS, Flexbox

Library Application | https://github.com/ethanwiegert/project-local-library

- -Assembled the functionality for an application that allows users to search, review and check out books from their local neighborhood.
- -Created search and sorting functions to allow users to know what books were available and their rating.
- -Coded using JavaScript functions that are built to enable the expansion of the library with little to no need for code refactoring.
- -Technology: JavaScript ES6, Bootstrap, HTML5, Node.js

Study Tool Application | https://github.com/ethanwiegert/flashcards-project

- -Created an application that allows users to create, edit, and delete decks and cards within them.
- -Created a REST API and middleware functions to allow user(s) to create, read, update and delete their perfect deck of study cards.
- -Defined routes and URLs, and used state over multiple components.
- -Technology: JavaScript, React, Express, Knex, HTML and CSS. Progress/ Versions tracked with Git.

### Exela Pharma Sciences LLC

Microbiologist I

August 2021 - August 2022 (1 year 1 month)

Lenoir, North Carolina, United States

- -Analyzed over 200 viable microbial samples associated with batches of medicine and the production environment.
- -Guided the department on improving training for laboratory tasks.
- -Analyzed over 30 out of trend or out of study results for the department and wrote respective occurrence documents.
- -Aided the team on all forms of testing from the raw material to the finished product.

## Education

Clemson University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Microbiology, General · (2017 - 2021)

Keio University

Certificate of Completion, Summer Program · (June 2019 - August 2019)